{
    "questions":[
        {
            "id": 0,
            "question": "How long have snakes been roaming the Earth?",
            "a":"3 million years",
            "b":"30 million years",
            "c":"130 million years",
            "d":"200 million years",
            "answerkey":"c"
        },
        {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "What characteristics do all snakes share?",
            "a":"They are carnivoes",
            "b":"They are all programming languages",
            "c":"They're all cold-blooded",
            "d":"They are both carnivores and cold-blooded",
            "answerkey":"c"
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "How snakes hear?",
            "a":"With small ears",
            "b":"Through their skin",
            "c":"Through their tail",
            "d":"They don't use their ears at all",
            "answerkey":"b"
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "What don't snakes see?",
            "a":"Colour",
            "b":"Light",
            "c":"Both of the above",
            "d":"Other snakes",
            "answerkey":"a"
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "What unique vision ability do boas and pythons possess?",
            "a":"Night vision",
            "b":"Infared vision",
            "c":"See through walls",
            "d":"They don't have vision",
            "answerkey":"b"
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "How does a snake smell?",
            "a":"Quite pleasant",
            "b":"Through its nose",
            "c":"Through its tongues",
            "d":"Both through its nose and its tongues",
            "answerkey":"d"
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "Where are Jacobson's organs located in snakes?",
            "a":"Mouth",
            "b":"Tail",
            "c":"Stomach",
            "d":"Liver",
            "answerkey":"a"
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "question": "Snakes have very similar internal organs compared to humans. Snakes, however; lack the following:",
            "a":"A diaphragm",
            "b":"Intestines",
            "c":"Lungs",
            "d":"Kidney",
            "answerkey":"a"
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "question": "Snakes have different shaped lungs than humans. What do snakes have?",
            "a":"An elongated right lung",
            "b":"A small left lung",
            "c":"Both of the above",
            "d":"None of the above",
            "answerkey":"c"
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "What's true about two-headed snakes?",
            "a":"They're a myth!",
            "b":"They rarely survive in the wild",
            "c":"They're very dangerous",
            "d":"They can kiss each other",
            "answerkey":"b"
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "What substance covers a snake's skin?",
            "a":"Calcium",
            "b":"Keratin",
            "c":"Copper",
            "d":"Iron",
            "answerkey":"b"
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "question": "What snake doesn't have to have a mate to lay eggs?",
            "a":"Copperhead",
            "b":"Cornsnake",
            "c":"Kingsnake",
            "d":"Flower pot snake",
            "answerkey":"d"
        },
        {
            "id": 12,
            "question": "What snake is the longest?",
            "a":"Green anaconda",
            "b":"Reticulated python",
            "c":"King cobra",
            "d":"Kingsnake",
            "answerkey":"b"
        },
        {
            "id": 13,
            "question": "Though invasive species can now be found in the Everglades, in which three continents are pythons (members of the family Pythonidae) found in the wild?",
            "a":"Africa, Asia and Australia",
            "b":"Africa, Australia and Europe",
            "c":"Africa, Australia and South America",
            "d":"Africa, Asia and South America",
            "answerkey":"a"
        },
        {
            "id": 14,
            "question": "Pythons are held as some of the most dangerous snakes on earth, but are often confused with anacondas. Which of these is *not* a difference between pythons and anacondas?",
            "a":"Pythons suffocate their prey, anacondas crush them",
            "b":"Pythons lay eggs, anacondas give birth to live young",
            "c":"Pythons grow longer, anacondas grow heavier",
            "d":"Pythons generally spend less time in water than anacondas do",
            "answerkey":"a"
        },
        {
            "id": 15,
            "question": "Pythons are unable to chew their food, and so swallow prey whole. Which of these methods is most commonly demonstrated to help a python to swallow large prey?",
            "a":"The python's stomach pressure is reduced, so prey is sucked in",
            "b":"An extra set of upper teeth 'walk' along the prey",
            "c":"The python holds its head up, so prey falls into its stomach",
            "d":"Prey is pushed against a barrier and is forced down the python's throat",
            "answerkey":"b"
        },
        {
            "id": 16,
            "question": "Pythons, like many large constrictors, possess vestigial hind limbs. Whilst these 'spurs' serve no purpose in locomotion, how are they put to use by some male pythons? ",
            "a":"To store sperm",
            "b":"To release pheromones",
            "c":"To grip females during mating",
            "d":"To fight off rival males",
            "answerkey":"c"
        },
        {
            "id": 17,
            "question": "Pythons tend to travel by the rectilinear method (in straight lines) when on land, as opposed to the concertina method (s-shaped movement). Why do large pythons tend not to use the concertina method? ",
            "a":"Their spine is too inflexible",
            "b":"They move too slowly",
            "c":"The scales on their backs are too rigid",
            "d":"They are too heavy",
            "answerkey":"d"
        }
    ]

}